通常当我发表公开讲话时，观众中的某个人会问我人工智能
Often when I give a public talk, somebody in the audience asks me about artificial intelligence
这不是一个我觉得特别舒服的话题。我认为自己
and it's not a subject I feel particularly comfortable to talk about. I consider myself
机器人专家，也就是建造机器的人，而人工智能
a roboticist, that is, somebody that builds machines, whereas artificial intelligence
对我来说，这是一门完全独立的学科，是计算机科学中的一门子学科。
to me is a completely separate discipline, a sub-discipline within computer science.
当然，情报也是一个非常难以理解的概念，我认为也是如此
Intelligence, of course, is also a very difficult concept to understand and I think it also
与历史背景有关。回到第一讲，我们看了
has something to do with the historical context. Way back in lecture number one, we looked
在这张着名的消化鸭的照片。那个时候，人们认为这个
at this picture of the famous digesting duck. And at that time, people considered that this
机器具有逼真的特性。无论它是否聪明，我都不确定，但是
machine had life-like properties. Whether it was intelligent or not, I'm not sure, but
人们认为它很像生活。
people considered it to be very life-like.
后来出现了这些自动机，非常复杂的机器，看起来很聪明
Later on came these automata, incredibly intricate machines that could do seemingly intelligent
的东西。也许在那个时候，人们会看着这些机器并考虑它们
things. And perhaps at that time, people would look at these machines and consider them to
聪明，因为他们做了智能生物或实体的各种事情，
be intelligent because they did the sorts of things that intelligent beings or entities,
比如人类，能够很容易地做到。
such as humans, are able to do quite readily.
在40年代末和50年代初期，WilliamGrayWalter建立了许多控制论设备，
In the late 40's and early 50's, William Grey Walter built a number of cybernetic devices,
最着名的是他的控制论乌龟。这是一台包含继电器和机器的机器
most famously his cybernetic tortoise. And this was a machine that contained relays and
真空管技术。
vacuum tube technology.
它能够展现寻光行为。所以，如果你在地板上放一盏灯，这只乌龟
It was able to exhibit light-seeking behavior. So if you put a light on the floor, this tortoise
当它到达那里时会朝着光线移动并停下来。所以再一次，这似乎是一个
would move towards the light and stop when it got there. So again, this was a seemingly
智能行为。在许多非常简单的生物体中可以看到这种寻光行为。
intelligent behavior. This light-seeking behavior is seen in many very simple organisms.
因此，当时，40年代末，50年代初期，这样的事情被认为是聪明的。
So at the time, late 40's, early 50's, something like this was perceived as being intelligent.
从我们目前的观点来看，它看起来相当原始和悲伤，但就此而言
Looking at it from our current viewpoint, it looks rather primitive and sad but at that
时间，我认为这是一个重大突破。
time, I think it was a significant breakthrough.
人工智能一词可能最初是在本研究提案中引入的
The term artificial intelligence was probably first introduced in this research proposal
从1955年开始，一群非常迫近的人，其中包括JohnMcCarthy和MarvinMinsky，
from 1955 by a bunch of very imminent people, amongst them John McCarthy and Marvin Minsky,
他们是人工智能社区中非常知名的人物。
who are very very well known names in the artificial intelligence community.
到1955年，数字计算机已成为现实，这群科学家对此感兴趣
By 1955, digital computers had become a reality and this group of scientists were interested
试图探索除了简单的数值计算之外他们能做些什么。所以
in trying to explore what could they do beyond straightforward numerical calculation. So
他们对神经网络，计算理论等问题感兴趣
they were interested in things like neural networks, theories of computation, could we
使用计算机进行自然语言处理，他们可以进行创造性的行为吗？
use computers to do natural language processing, could they perform acts of creativity?
通过查看他们建议调查的主题列表，您会注意到什么
What you'll notice from looking at the list of topics that they proposed to investigate
在他们的夏季项目中，没有提到机器人，也没有提到计算机
in their summer project was there's no mention of robotics and there is no mention of computer
视力。原因是这两件事尚未发明。
vision. The reason for that is that those two things had not yet been invented.
我们今天所知的第一台工业机器人是由UnimationInc.开发的。
The first industrial robot as we know it today was developed by Unimation Inc.
直到1956年，该公司才成立，
and that company wasn't even formed until 1956,
人工智能项目和Unimation在1961年交付了第一台机器人一年后。
one year after the artificial intelligence project and Unimation delivered its first robot in 1961.
但此后，其他一些机器人出现了相当快速的连续性。
But thereafter, a number other robots appeared in quite rapid succession.
它们都是在斯坦福大学的人工智能实验室开发的
They were all developed within artificial intelligence laboratories at Stanford and
麻省理工学院和这些机器人设计师中的主要成员是设计ORM的VictorScheinman
at MIT and chief amongst these robot designers was Victor Scheinman who designed the ORM
和ORM我相信，蛇是挪威人，他还在1968年设计了着名的斯坦福大学。
and ORM I believe, is Norwegian for snake and he also designed the very famous Stanford arm in 1968.
1964年，计算机视觉开始于麻省理工学院LarryRoberts的博士学位。
Computer vision really got its start in 1964 with the PhD work of Larry Roberts at MIT.
他有兴趣了解计算机如何解释块世界。所以一台相机
He was interested in understanding how computers could interpret a blocks world. So a camera
连接到计算机将采用场景的灰度图像和各种各样的
attached to a computer would take a gray-scale image of a scene and with various sorts of
早期的图像处理算法，可以找到边缘，然后拟合模型。拉里
early image processing algorithms, could find the edges and then fit a model to that. Larry
罗伯茨继续在创建互联网方面做了很多伟大的事情。
Roberts went on to do really great things in the creation of the Internet.
那么，什么是情报？我可以查看字典并获得定义
So then, what is intelligence? I can look in the dictionary and get a definition of
情报，但对我来说，这不是特别有帮助。我想我们假设是人类
intelligence, but to me, this is not particularly helpful. I think we assume that human beings
因此，人类表现出来的行为就像智慧一样。
are intelligent so therefore, the behaviors manifest by human beings count as intelligence.
但是我们知道有很多动物可以表现出智能行为
But we know that there are many animals that can exhibit intelligent behavior and it's
在越来越多的简单动物中被发现。曾几何时，我们相信也许是这样
been found in more and more simple animals. Once upon a time, we believed it was perhaps
只有能够表现出某种智力的巨猿，但现在科学家才有
only the great apes that could exhibit some sort of intelligence but now scientists have
在各种物种中都发现了相当聪明的行为。即使是鸟类也能够流行
found quite intelligent behaviors in all manner of species. Even birds are able to fashion
简单的工具，帮助他们完成特定的任务。
simple tools to help them to achieve particular tasks.
我特别喜欢的定义来自罗德尼布鲁克斯，那就是情报
A definition I particularly like comes from Rodney Brooks and that is that intelligence
是在旁观者的眼中。所以，如果你正在看一台机器做一些任务而你
is in the eye of the beholder. So if you're looking at a machine doing some task and you
认为它是聪明的，那么它是聪明的。
think it's intelligent, then it is intelligent.
也许最着名的智能定义是图灵测试，它是由提出来的
Perhaps the best known definition of intelligence is the Turing test and it was proposed by
英国数学家艾伦·图灵（AlanTuring）在1950年的一篇名为“计算机械与计算机械”的论文中
the English mathematician, Alan Turing, in a 1950 paper called Computing Machinery and
情报。在那篇特别的论文中，他提出了一种叫做模仿游戏的东西，
Intelligence. In that particular paper, he proposed something called the imitation game,
当然，这是最近关于阿兰图灵生平的电影的名字。
and of course that's the name of the recent movie about the life of Alan Turing.
游戏中有三个玩家：A是正在接受智力测试的计算机，B
The game has three players: A is a computer which is being tested for intelligence, B
是一个真正的人，而C是法官。法官不知道A或B中的哪一个
is a real human being, and C is the judge. The judge doesn't know which of A or B is
计算机，所以问A和B的问题，试图确定哪个是哪个。
the computer and so asks questions of A and B to try and determine which is which.
为了掩盖关于A或B中的哪一个是计算机，游戏的真正明显的线索
In order to mask the really obvious cues about which one of A or B is the computer, the game
通常使用键盘和屏幕通信进行播放，因此没有语言通信。
is generally played with keyboard and screen communication, so there's no verbal communications.
判断器在键盘上键入命令，A或B响应屏幕上显示的信息。
The judge types commands on a keyboard, A or B respond with information displayed on a screen.
现在，如果法官在提出足够的问题后，无法确定哪一项
Now if the judge, after asking sufficient questions, is unable to determine which of
A或B是计算机，然后计算机被认为是智能的，因为法官，
A or B is the computer, then the computer is deemed to be intelligent because the judge,
谁是聪明的，无法区分它和真正的人类。
who is intelligent, is unable to tell the difference between it and a real human being.